<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Diary of a Data Scientist</title>
    <link>/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Diary of a Data Scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding Ontologies</title>
      <link>/posts/adding_ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adding_ontologies/</guid>
      <description>I discovered Hugo when reviewing Hugo in Action from Manning. But I understood the potential of the tool only when looking for a theme for a new site — and then discoveries the different ontologies that were normally supported.
For this site, I discovered that
Series of posts are supported, Tags, and Categories I wanted to use all of them, thus I started by including in all the posts a different incipit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Plots to a Post</title>
      <link>/posts/adding_plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adding_plots/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of the main requirements in order to publish Jupyter notebooks is to be able to attach images to the posts. In this post, I focus on how to attach images, and in finding a standard for the images (like fonts, background and style).
Attaching an image In order to attach an image to a post, I follow this guide. I create a folder for the images under the static folder:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Markdown Tables to a Post</title>
      <link>/posts/adding_tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adding_tables/</guid>
      <description>The intent of using Markdown and Hugo for my site is to directly export from a Jupyter notebook into a post. However, when I preview a dataframe with head and export the notebook, I obtain a HTML table that is not nicely rendered or styled. The intent is to export in pure Markdown, and let the Hugo theme dictate what the aspect of the table should be.
The naive approach I start with the creation of a pandas dataframe in the first cell of a notebook:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding LaTeX capabilities</title>
      <link>/posts/adding_latex_capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adding_latex_capabilities/</guid>
      <description>I find very complicated to write about Data Science without using mathematical formulas. That is why I think that the Medium editor is very unconvenient for scientific writing. While obviously there are many pubblications on Data Science, the articles turns to be quite shallow in term of details. I love and daily read from Towards Data Science and MLearning.ai, there is an obvious restraint from writing too much Math-dense articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a new site</title>
      <link>/posts/building_this_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/building_this_site/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post on my site, and I dedicate it to describe step by step how I created it. I use Hugo and simple Markdown — and quite a lot of command line. I am working on a testing Debian (WSL, to be specific).
How to set up the site To start I install hugo,
sudo apt-get install hugo hugo version	The version I am using at the time of writing this is:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
